First, let's look at what the gradient descent algorithm is doing.
首先 我们看看梯度下降算法在干什么
So, recall that we're up here in the top of Mount Everest and we need to go down.
我们位于珠峰山顶上 需要下山
In order to go down,
为了下山
we take a bunch of steps following the negative of the gradient of the height,
我们按照高度（即误差函数）的梯度负值的方向
which is the error function.
走了很多步
Each step is called an epoch.
每步就叫做 epoch
So, when we refer to the number of steps,
当我们提到步长次数时
we refer to the number of epochs.
我们指的是 epoch 次数
Now, let's see what happens in each epoch.
现在我们看看每个 epoch 中发生的情况
In each epoch, we take our input,
在每个 epoch 中 我们获得输入
namely all of our data and run it through the entire neural network.
即所有的数据 让其完成整个神经网络
Then we find our predictions,
然后算出预测
we calculate the error, namely,
我们计算误差
how far they are from where their actual labels.
即与实际标签相差多大
And finally, we back-propagate this error in order
最后 我们反向传播此误差
to update the weights in the neural network.
以便更新神经网络中的权重
This will give us a better boundary for predicting our data.
这样将会提供更好的界线来预测数据
Now this is done for all the data.
对所有数据完成这一过程
If we have many, many data points,
如果有很多很多的数据点
which is normally the case,
通常都是这样
then these are huge matrix computations,
那么这些就是很大的矩阵计算过程
I'd use tons and tons of memory and all that just for a single step.
我会用到大量的内存 而这仅仅是一个步长
If we had to do many steps,
如果有很多步长
you can imagine how this would take a long time and lots of computing power.
可以想象要花费多少时间和运算容量
Is there anything we can do to expedite this?
有没有什么方法可以加速这一过程？
Well, here's a question: do we need to plug in all our data every time we take a step?
有个问题：每次进行一个步长 都需要代入所有数据吗？
If the data is well distributed,
如果数据分布很合理
it's almost like a small subset of it would give us
那么一小部分数据就可以很好地告诉我们
a pretty good idea of what the gradient would be.
梯度是多少
Maybe it's not the best estimate for the gradient but it's quick,
或许不是最准确的梯度估算结果 但是速度很快
and since we're iterating,
因为我们要迭代计算
it may be a good idea.
或许是个好方法
This is where stochastic gradient descent comes into play.
这时候随机梯度下降就派上用场了
The idea behind stochastic gradient descent is simply that we take small subsets of data,
随机梯度下降的原理很简单
run them through the neural network,
我们拿出一小部分数据 让它们经历整个神经网络
calculate the gradient of the error function based on
根据这些点计算误差函数的梯度
those points and then move one step in that direction.
然后沿着该方向移动一个步长
Now, we still want to use all our data, so,
现在我们依然要使用所有数据
what we do is the following;
所以我们的做法是
we split the data into several batches.
我们将数据拆分为几个批次
In this example, we have 24 points.
在此示例中 我们有 24 个点
We'll split them into four batches of six points.
我们将拆分为 4 批 每批 6 个点
Now we take the points in the first batch and run them through the neural network,
拿出第一批次的点并用神经网络处理它们
calculate the error and its gradient and back-propagate to update the weights.
计算误差和梯度 反向传播以更新权重
This will give us new weights,
这样就得出新的权重
which will define a better boundary region as you can see on the left.
它们将定义出更好的界限区域 从左侧可以看出
Now, we take the points in the second batch and we do the same thing.
现在拿出第二批次的数据 完成相同的流程
This will again give us better weights and a better boundary region.
得出更好的权重和更好的界限区域
Now, we do the same thing for the third batch.
然后对第三批次执行相同的流程
And finally, we do it for the fourth batch and we're done.
最后对第四批次执行相同的流程 就完成了
Notice that with the data,
注意对于数据
we took four steps whereas,
我们执行了 4 个步长
when we did normal gradient descent,
但是对于普通梯度下降
we took only one step with all the data.
我们仅对所有数据执行了一个步长
Of course, the four steps we took were less accurate but in the practice,
当然 所采取的四个步长精确度很低
it's much better to take a bunch of slightly inaccurate steps than to take one good one.
但在现实中 采取大量稍微不太准确的步长比采取一个很准确的步长要好很多
Later in this nanodegree, you'll have the chance to apply
在此纳米学位课程的稍后阶段
stochastic gradient descents and really see the benefits of it.
你将有机会应用随机梯度下降 看看它的优势